do you remember last year when a company
that was funded by the Australian
military immersed tiny human brains
grown in jars in Game World demonstrated
that they were sentient but also kind of
sort of created The Matrix well it's
gotten a lot better what you're seeing
behind me is a virtual world where brain
organoids were given a butterfly body
they're receiving sensory input from a
game World they weren't trained or
taught to do this they were just given
the body if they were to think they were
anything they would probably think
they're a butterfly yes this is the very
same Swiss company that is selling brain
organoid computation as a subscription
model where you can rent out 16 tiny
brains and have them work for you this
is truly an amazing feat in computation
engineering and biological sciences but
we are essentially creating and
perfecting The Matrix I actually found
out about this because final spark let
me join their Discord and I'm waiting
for them to regret it please don't kick
me out of Discord if this kind of
progress happened in a year imagine
where we'll be in 10 this tells us a lot
about how we can connect a human brain
to machines they also sent me this video
this is one of the very first brain
organoid robots this all happened around
2008 a brain in a jar is remotely
controlling this little guy here this is
what happens when we give them sensory
input in the real world I've also been
informed that these are technically
cyborgs I really give it just one year
before somebody pops it into a humanoid
robot if it hasn't already been done